<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>engineering excellence on Amit Kumar</title><link>https://toamitkumar.github.io/tags/engineering-excellence/</link><description>Recent content in engineering excellence on Amit Kumar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://toamitkumar.github.io/tags/engineering-excellence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building &amp; scaling Engineering team</title><link>https://toamitkumar.github.io/2021/12/09/building-and-scaling-engineering-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.github.io/2021/12/09/building-and-scaling-engineering-team/</guid><description>The first batch of the series of 5 blog posts describing the journey to build an Engineering setup in Financial Services. Read the preface to get a clear context of the journey.
Building and scaling Engineering team: Principles and practices adopted to build the product and engineering team Technology choices &amp;amp; Engineering practices: We took an outward-in approach to establish the foundation of technology stack, architecture/ design choices &amp;amp; engineering practices Infrastructure: The core principle was IAC (Infrastructure as Code).</description></item><item><title>Building an Engineering setup in Financial Services</title><link>https://toamitkumar.github.io/2021/12/09/building-engineering-setup-financial-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.github.io/2021/12/09/building-engineering-setup-financial-services/</guid><description>I have been part of building Product &amp;amp; Engineering teams and Digital Transformation setup for almost more than a decade.
My first experience was during the build of MDL (McKinsey Digital Labs) by our leaders: Satty Bhens and Biju Bhaskar - a startup like setup (for both engineering setup and business building) inside a large organisation. They both are strong believers of garage-like setup and gave full support to establish guard-rails in protecting the culture of working like a startup.</description></item></channel></rss>