<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tops on Amit Kumar</title><link>https://toamitkumar.in/top/</link><description>Recent content in Tops on Amit Kumar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://toamitkumar.in/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://toamitkumar.in/top/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.in/top/about/</guid><description>Amit Kumar has been in Engineering setup for almost 2 decades. He is an open-source enthusiast with passion on building large-scale (more than 10-15 million customers), cross-country platforms/systems across various industries.
He enjoys speaking at Developer and Open Source Technology Conferences worldwide. Some of the talks can be referred below or here. He is co-founder of Open Source Not-for-profit community JSChannel - organizes meet-ups and conferences.
He is strong believer of:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://toamitkumar.in/top/community/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.in/top/community/</guid><description>Community (organizing, co-founder) I have been involved in organizing conefenrences &amp;amp; user-groups, at the same time an avid speaker as well.
Recently, I gave a talk on Creating DevOps Culture In A Bank at DevOpsDays Singapore
Below are links to a few events I organize or given talks:
Organizer of DevOpsDays Jakarta: first devops conference in Indonesia Speaker at DevOpsDays Singapore Organizer of JSChannel Conference 2017 Organizer of JSChannel Conference 2016 Organizer of JSChannel Conference 2015 Organizer of JSChannel Conference 2014 Organizer of JSChannel Conference 2013 Speaker at first RubyMotion Conferece in Brussels Speaker at Ruby Conference Australia Speaker at Ruby Conference San Francisco Speaker at Ruby Conference New Orleans MongoDB Conference Philadelphia</description></item><item><title/><link>https://toamitkumar.in/top/speaking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.in/top/speaking/</guid><description>2015 Digital Transformation of an Enterprise - 2 speed IT &amp;amp; Agile
2013 RubyMotion Coference, Brussels RubyMotion - Building Interactive Data Visualization Charts
Ruby Conference, Australia Using Ruby for Native iOS Development (sessions)
2012 Goldengate Ruby Conference, San Francisco Rubyizing iOS development (sessions)
2011 Ruby Ruby Conference, New Orleans MongoDB Conference, New Orleans Micro-Blogging Solution for the Enterprise (sessions)</description></item><item><title>Posts Archive</title><link>https://toamitkumar.in/top/archive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://toamitkumar.in/top/archive/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>